A Guide to the Material By and About Warren Chappell, 1937-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Material By and About Warren Chappell 1937-1999
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
10204-bl
The collection contains ca. 75 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was transferred from Rare Books on April 23, 2004.
Scope and Content
The collection contains material (ca. 75 items, 1937-1999) by and about Warren Chappell either laid in or accompanying books from his library.
Contents List
- Bound Volume, Typographic trial for Romeo and Juliet in a Shakespeare series, dummy partially printed ca. 1940 (Box 1)
- Bound Volume, Mock-up of Three For Jack 1947 (Box 1)
- Bound Volume, Sample Book Binding from Kingsport Press, Inc., Kingsport, Tennessee for Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. Project 1969 (Box 1)
- Bound Volume, Original Drawings for Don Quixote by Warren Chappell in a Sample Book Binding from Kingsport Press, Inc., Kingsport, Tennessee for Alfred A. Knopf, Inc. Project ca. 1969 (Box 1)
- Bound Volume, Book-of-the-Month-Club publication dummies (2 volumes) n.d. (Box 1)
- Bound Volume, Blank Book in which four pages of Mr. Midshipman Easy by Frederick Marryat were pasted in n.d. (Box 1)
- Catalog of Books in the Library of Lydia and Warren Chappell 1978 (Box 1)
- Copies of Illustrations from Rembrandt Des Meisters Hanzeichnungen Volume I Herausgegeben von Wilhelm R. Valentiner [1925?] (Box 1)
- Correspondence, Robert Barancik, New Penn Press, to Warren Chappell 1984 Feb 29 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Isabel Bishop to Warren Chappell 1976 Oct 16 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Warren Chappell to Joan Crane 197[2] Dec 6 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Bill Haynes to Warren Chappell n.d. (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Julius Held to Lydia Chappell 1984 Apr 5 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Alfred A. Knopf and Blanche W. Knopf to Warren Chappell 1948, 1974 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Fritz Kredel to Lydia and Warren Chappell 1937-1938 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Miscellaneous Correspondents to Warren Chappell 1937-1989, n.d. (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Philip Reed to Warren Chappell 1959 Feb 26 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Leopold Tyrmand to Lydia and Warren Chappell n.d. (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Lynd Ward to Warren Chappell 1975 Jun 22 (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Berthold Wolpe to Lydia and Warren Chappell, including a design by Wolpe 1975 Aug 8, n.d. (Box 2)
- Correspondence, Hermann Zapf to Warren Chappell 1974 Nov 30 (Box 2)
- Drawings and Artwork n.d. (Box 2)
- Miscellaneous 1948, n.d. (Box 2)
- "Notes on a Nude 1962" by Isabel Bishop 1962 (Box 2)
- Papers pertaining to the exhibit "The Imprints of Gloomth" in the Tracy W. McGregor Room at the Alderman Library, University of Virginia which featured the Sadleir-Black Gothic Novel Collection 1988 (Box 2)
- The Silver Jubilee Citation to Warren Chappell from the Limited Editions Club 1954 May 11 (Box 2)